<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<language id="44">
<page id="8384" title="Litcube's Rival Corporation Artificial Life" descr="">
 <t id="1">Litcube's Phanon Corporation</t>
 <t id="2">Phanon</t>
 <t id="15">[author][green]Phanon Corporation[/green][/author]Dear %s,\n\nOn Behalf of the Phanon Corporation, I, Zalex Yhulan would express our deepest regrets over your previous actions. Know that the Phanon Corporation will return soon with doubled efforts.</t>
 <t id="23">The %s Headquarters</t>
 <t id="24">[author][green]**Unknown Sender**[/green][/author]Dear %s,\n\nOn behalf of my employer who will remain anonymous, I am forwarding a considerably large financial sum of %s to your account. Consider it a token of my employer's appreciation for dealing with The Phanon Corporation's latest puppet company. My employer's interests and yours seem to be aligned on one path or another, so I expect to be in touch with you at a future date.</t>
 <t id="26">[author][green]**Unknown Sender**[/green][/author]Dear %s,\n\nI would like to extend my congratulations on behalf of my employer, who can only remain anonymous at this time. It is of my employers understanding that with the defeat of the Phanon Corporation parent company, the X Universe has finally seen the last of this unbalancing menace. As a final reward to the end of a long journey, please accept this donation of %s to your company from ours. Take care, pilot, and farewell.</t>
 <t id="27">[author][green]GNN[/green][/author]In a surprising turn of events, Phanon Corporation subsidiary %s was removed from office today. While the subsidiary CEO could not be reached for comment, sources say the firing was due to a recent decline in fiscal performance.</t>
 <t id="101">TandiTech</t>
 <t id="102">Nova Ltd.</t>
 <t id="103">Vashire</t>
 <t id="104">Rhayl Plex</t>
 <t id="105">Omicron Ltd.</t>
 <t id="106">Megax</t>
 <t id="107">Syndex</t>
 <t id="108">Phanon</t>
 <t id="201">[author][green]TandiTech Corporation[/green][/author]Dear %s,\n\nOn Behalf of The TandiTech Corporation, a subsidiary of The Phanon Corporation, I, Kyrdall Kormal, Chairman, would like to take this opportunity to personally extend to you my warmest greetings and well wishes. Certain sponsors have put forth a venture capital of %s to initiate our organization. As free-market trade law mandates, it is our duty to inform you that our company has established itself with an operation headquarters in sector %s, and will be expanding from there as our board of directors deem fit and as warranted by our financial accrual. We would also like to offer you a friendly reminder to please keep clear of our property, including trade ships, warships, and stations, as the free market can be a difficult, demanding, and often dangerous place. Here at TandiTech, your safety is important to us.\n\nWarmest regards,\nKyrdall Kormal</t>
 <t id="202">[author][green]Nova Ltd. Corporation[/green][/author]Dear %s,\n\nOn Behalf of The Nova Ltd. Corporation, a subsidiary of The Phanon Corporation, I, Tastad Nova, Chairman, would like to inform you that your relations of our previous late sister company, The TandiTech Corporation, can be forgiven and forgotten. I'm sure our business transactions will not come within each other's way this time. To ensure our success, The Phanon Corporation has granted us a larger salary than expected, which does not include a venture capital of %s.\n\nWarmest regards,\nTastad Nova</t>
 <t id="203">[author][green]Vashire Corporation[/green][/author]Dear %s,\n\nOn Behalf of The Vashire Corporation, a subsidiary of The Phanon Corporation, I, Klhuad, CEO, would extend my deepest regrets for any properties and assets owned by you that met an early demise at the hands of our security forces. I'm sure this misunderstanding will not come between The Phanon Corporations latest venture. As dictated by Universal trade law, records will indicate our venture capital grant from the Phanon Corporation to be %s.\n\nWarmest regards,\nKlhuad</t>
 <t id="204">[author][green]Rhayl Plex Corporation[/green][/author]Dear %s,\n\nOn Behalf of The Rhayl Plex Corporation, a subsidiary of The Phanon Corporation, I, Om Ido, CEO, am warning you. I'm an old school businessmen, have attended various Teladi economic universities, and have a resume the size of a transport ship. Venture capital from Phanon Corp. at this point is %s, but you can look that up yourself. Stay away from our assets.\n\nWarmest regards,\nOm Ido</t>
 <t id="205">[author][green]Omicron Ltd. Corporation[/green][/author]%s,\n\nI have very little to say to you. The Phanon Corporation is investing %s this time around. Stay away, or face the consequences. I, Perdis Lhuan, CEO of The Omicron Ltd. Corporation, have taken hold of an outpost. We've established a frontier, and you will not hinder The Phanon Corporation's ventures any further.\n\n\nPerdis Lhuan</t>
 <t id="206">[author][green]Megax Corporation[/green][/author]%s,\n\nStay clear of our ships. The Megax Corporation's grant of %s has no time to waste on the likes of your company. This is a warning.\n\n\nXag Khurmagaun</t>
 <t id="207">[author][green]Syndex Corporation[/green][/author]%s,\n\nThis is simply the obligitory message we're required to send by inter-stellar trade law. Phanon Corporation's grant of %s, forwarded to us recently. Nothing more, nothing less.\n\n\nNaydol Ulmankstal</t>
 <t id="208">[author][green]The Phanon Corporation[/green][/author]%s,\n\nSo it has come to this, has it? The full weight of The Phanon Corporation is behind the our final venture of %s. You and your affiliates are marked as an official security threat, and will be dealt with accordingly. Your actions will not stop our take-overs, so we have finally decided to step in, throwing our full weight behind our endeavours.\n\n\nZalex Yhulan</t>
 <t id="250">[author][green]%s[/green][/author][cyan]**Broadcast Message**[/cyan]\nAs per inter-stellar trade law, we are issuing financial and asset statements to registered parties, including an Argon Military Threat Assessment model, as per Argon Military Registration by-laws. All registrations are fully legal; certification provided upon request.\n\n</t>
 <t id="251">Corporation: [red]The Phanon Corporation[/red]\n</t>
 <t id="252">Active subsidiary: [red]%s[/red]\n\n</t>
 <t id="253">Credit balance: [white]%s[/white]\n</t>
 <t id="254">Liquid assets: [white]%s[/white]\n</t>
 <t id="255">Next scheduled procurement: [white]%s[/white]\n\n</t>
 <t id="256">Registered free agent traders: [white]%s[/white]\n</t>
 <t id="257">Registered station sales representatives: [white]%s[/white]\n</t>
 <t id="258">Registered factories: [white]%s[/white]\n</t>
 <t id="259">Registered military assets: [white]%s[/white]\n</t>
 <t id="260">AMTA Index: [white]%s[/white]</t>
 <t id="300">3,15</t>
 <t id="301">8,16</t>
 <t id="302">11,14</t>
 <t id="303">9,16</t>
 <t id="304">9,7</t>
 <t id="305">8,8</t>
 <t id="306">12,5</t>
 <t id="307">16,16</t>
 <t id="308">4,6</t>
 <t id="309">6,6</t>
 <t id="310">10,16</t>
 <t id="311">7,10</t>
 <t id="312">8,12</t>
 <t id="320">240</t>
 <t id="349">15</t> <!-- Phanon Starting Cash in Millions : Default=15 -->
 <t id="350">2500</t> <!-- Phanon Salary per tick base = $4000 + ({id="350"} * $PhanonGeneration) : Default=2500 -->
 <t id="351">225</t>
 <t id="352">1080</t>
 <t id="353">1</t>
 <t id="354">500</t>
 <t id="355">1500</t>
 <t id="356">2750</t>
 <t id="357">4625</t>
 <t id="358">7438</t>
 <t id="359">11656</t>
 <t id="360">17984</t>
</page>
<page id="8387" title="SWLU Text" descr="Used by SWLU">
 <t id="1">SWLU Initialization Scripts</t>
 <t id="15">[author][red]XenonArchitect7[/red][/author]Hello, %s!\n\nWelcome to Star Wars LU [green]version 1.2.9![/green] This is a total conversion mod for Litcube's Universe that aims to bring Star Wars into the world of X3. If you have bugs to report or need help, please feel free to reach out on the SWLU Discord.\n\n[cyan] GiC Version 1.1.3 [/cyan]\n\n[cyan]----SWLU Mod Team----[/cyan]\nXenonArchitect7 - Lead mod dev\nTormox - Animated shield texture, help with various large ship models\nLeytra - Help with some light maps, textures\nRocket Man - Discord moderator, testing, Prophet of Droidism\nArgonaut0201 - Author of &quot;SWLU Galaxy in Chaos&quot; official expansion\nPurls - Author of &quot;SWLU The Clone Wars&quot; official expansion\n\n[cyan] GiC Credit[/cyan]\nXenonArchitect7 - General modding assistance\nPurls - Ideas and script help\ntemetvince - Helped fix stock exhange.\nLeytra - Icy planet texture\nRocket Man - script testing\nXDeadShotX - Early testing\n-Wolfie - Testing\n\n[cyan]----Ship/Asset Models Credit----[/cyan]\nWarb Null\nDinoff\nJeroenimo\nMaxloef1990\nMikhail Skatchkov\nPSCO1\nSwefan Italia\nKlaus11\n\n[cyan]----Special Thanks----[/cyan]\nLitcube - Creator of LU, made all this possible\nJoubarbe - Author of Mayhem mod, invaluable help\nHector0x - Mayhem2 port testing and feedback\nScarps - Early help with audio and TIE cockpit textures\nTheXPGamers - Public testing and spreading the word</t>
 <t id="16">[author][red]XenonArchitect7[/red][/author]\n\nWell, well, well. Looks like your curiosity got the better of you. The menu clearly states that this gamestart is not yet finished, and yet here you are. Snooping around in the upcoming content.\n\nI am going to have to come and deal with you myself. There is no escape from retribution for you now.</t>
 <t id="17">[author][red]XenonArchitect7[/red][/author]\n\nYou're not getting away that easily.</t>
 <t id="18">[author][red]XenonArchitect7[/red][/author]Congratulations, %s!\n\nCongrats on beating LU! Not many players make it this far or ever see this screen. If you would like to be included in the SWLU Discord &quot;SWLU Veteran&quot; role, please send a direct message to XenonArchitect7#0904 with the code [green]4H8DQ[/green]. I'll know what that means. This lets me know for personal reference which version of SWLU people are beating the game on.\n\nThere are countless ways to cheat, exploit, bypass, or cheese the OCV. No justificaiton is needed for the rank, but I at least hope you didn't ruin the fun for yourself and at had some massive fleet battles to enjoy.\n\n-Argonaut0201-\n\nAhem, now that is out of the way. If you haven't noticed already, you have just beaten the game. Regardless of the troubles, the constant movement, and entirely new dynamic of the galaxy, you pulled through and put an end to the existential threat to the universe. All while in the midst of one of the most deadly wars this galaxy has ever seen. Especially if you went through the game facing every one of your hardships without any help of any exploits or cheats.\n\nCongratulations, you just beat SWLU: Hard Mode.</t>
 <t id="19">[author]Personal Log Entry[/author]\n[green]------| Deluded Scoundrel |------[/green]\nNobody believed it was real. Nobody wanted to join you in your hunt. But finally, after searching desperately across the galaxy and making many enemies in the process, you have obtained the treasure map. According to its ancient markings, it points you towards the ruins of the Firefist cluster. May you find your way there, you will find bountiful treasures and a paradise far from the chaos of the galaxy.</t>
 <t id="20">debug</t>
</page>
<page id="8389" title="GiC Random Scripted Events" descr="">
 <t id="1">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nAfter recent miscommunications and accidental attacks on Mandalorian shipping over the past few weeks, the Mandalorian government has severed all formal ties with the Imperial government and has formed an active rebellion against imperial control. Rebel Alliance ships, which had previously been denied legal entry to mandalorian space, are now being sent to aid the Mandalorian efforts.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="2">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nAfter a recent breakdown of relations between the Rebel Alliance and the Corporate sector, the Corporate Sector, seeing no need to continue its neutrality towards the Alliance, has began open hostilities against the Rebels.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="3">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nAfter a recent breakdown of relations between the Galactic Empire and the Corporate sector, the Corporate Sector, seeing no need to continue its ties with the Empire, has began to openly support the Rebel Alliance.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="4">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nSucceeding a breakdown of trade agreements between the Mandalorian dynasty and the Corporate Sector, the two factions have declared hostilities and severed ties between each other.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="5">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nWith recent campaigns by both the Rebel Alliance and the Corporate Sector proving to be ineffective, both sides have signed a temporary truce and end to hostilities.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="6">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nWith recent campaigns by both the Galactic Empire and the Corporate Sector proving to be ineffective, both sides have signed a temporary truce and end to hostilities.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="7">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nAfter recent miscommunications and accidental attacks on Mandalorian shipping over the past few weeks, the Mandalorian government has severed all formal ties with the Rebel Alliance and has joined arms with the Galactic Empire in stamping out the Rebellion.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="8">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nSome time after the Mandalorians' efforts to eliminate the Rebel Alliance took place, dissent among the Mandalorian population grew. This evening, this dissent culminated in a rebellion against the Mandalorian leadership, with many Mandalorian ships joining the Rebel Alliance.\n\n[red]Begins the Mandalorian Civil War[/red]\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="9">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nAfter the massive instability and failures that came after the Mandalorian entry into the Galactic Civil War, the Mandalorian has retracted its hostilities and signed a formal truce. Those who defected from the Mandalorian government will not be given official pardons.\n\n[red]Ends the Mandalorian Civil War[/red]\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="10">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\n\nSome time after the Mandalorians' efforts to eliminate the Galactic Empire took place, dissent among the Mandalorian population grew. This evening, this dissent culminated in a rebellion against the Mandalorian leadership, with many Mandalorian ships being merged into Imperial forces.\n\n[red]Begins the Mandalorian Civil War[/red]\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="11">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nToday at the head assembly of the Old Republic Collector's League in Malachor, the &quot;leaders&quot; of the loose band of collectors were assasinated today by an unknown group of individuals. The details and implications of this assasination has yet to have surfaced.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="12">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nAfter the recent assasination of the leaders of the Old Republic, most of the forces of the Old Republic have been taken over by the newly formed Sith Khanate, which has formed as a result of the power vacuum created after the assasination.\n\nAs of yet, we have not heard of this new government's intentions.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="13">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nToday the Sith Khanate's leadership addressed the many shocked members of the former Old Republic. One individual, who has branded himself the &quot;Great Khan&quot; has stated his intentions to restore the &quot;glory days&quot; of the Sith clans, and that a new age has been born.\n\nThe Sith Khanate has declared war on the galaxy.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="14">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\nIn a recent turn of events, the leaders of the Sith Khanate have been killed. Whether this was due to an assasination or a result of a battle is not yet known. \n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.\n</t>
 <t id="15">[author][red]SITH KHANATE CONTINGENCY TRANSMISSION[/red][/author]\nATTENTION ALL SUBJECTS,\nSITH KHANATE LEADERSHIP CONFIRMED MISSING.\nCONTINGENCY PLAN 1A IN EFFECT.\n\nALL SUBJECTS ARE TO REPORT TO TRAVEL TO EMERGENCY COORDINATES IN THE UNKNOWN REGION.\nHYPERLANE DATA WILL BE DELIVERED SHORTLY.</t>
</page>
<page id="8390" title="GiC Static Events" descr="">
 <t id="1">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\n\nHaving been able to hold off the Hutts on the ground for hundreds of years, the Free Saki Defence Force \(FSDF\) has liberated the space around their planet with the help of the Rebel Alliance, and has thus joined galactic affairs as a Rebel sympathetic world.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="2">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\n\nHaving been able to hold off the Hutts on the ground for hundreds of years, the Free Saki Defence Force \(FSDF\) has liberated the space around their planet with the help of the Galactic Empire, and has thus joined galactic affairs as an Imperial territory.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="4">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\n\nIn a recent schism on the old droid producing world of Mechis III, the Empire has liberated the planet of pirate influence.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="5">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\n\nWith the Jedi order spread thin and defeated, the last bastion of the order, above the planet Tython is now under seige by forces of the Galactic Empire.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.</t>
 <t id="7">[author][white]Galactic News[/white][/author]\n\nAfter months of sustained conflict near the Hutt territories, the Belasco system, an Imperial stronghold, has caved in to mounting asssaults by nearby Pirates, as well as the Rebel Alliance aided by the remaining forces of the Confederacy of Independent Systems stationed in Attahox.\n\nThe exact implications of this loss cannot be exactly determined, but what is for sure is that Imperial influence in the area has diminished severely.\n\nStay tuned for further updates on galactic affairs.\n</t>
</page>
<page id="8391" title="GiC Raid" descr="">
 <t id="1">%s %s Neutralized: %s %s Cr\n</t>
 <t id="2">Shipping</t>
 <t id="3">Personnel Transport</t>
 <t id="4">Supply</t>
 <t id="5">Base</t>
 <t id="6">Production</t>
 <t id="7">Military</t>
 <t id="8">Military</t>
 <t id="9">Imperial</t>
 <t id="10">Rebel</t>
 <t id="11">Corporate Sector</t>
 <t id="12">1000</t>
 <t id="13">Xenon</t>
 <t id="14">Criminal</t>
 <t id="15">Trade Federation</t>
 <t id="16">Techno Union</t>
 <t id="17">Intergalactic Banking Clan</t>
 <t id="201">5</t>
</page>
</language>
