<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<language id="44">
<page id="350037" title="Encyclopedia Texts" descr="">
 <t id="62">Mod Mechanics</t>
 <t id="63">Litcube`s Universe Wiki</t>
 <t id="64">Star Wars Wiki</t>
 <t id="65">Credits</t>
 <t id="66">Meow</t>
</page>
<page id="9981" title="Mayhem Encyclopedia (SWLU CONVERT)" descr="">
 <t id="1">Bounce</t>
 <t id="2">Litcube`s Universe comes equipped with a hard-coded system to mitigate the hazard of ships colliding with other objects.\n\n\033OI`ve Heard of This Before!\033X\n\nAs you may be aware from the Egosoft forums, Bounce was a script package that helped alleviate some of the frustration caused by default ship behavior. Ships in vanilla would run headlong into an opposing capital ship to uphold their honor in a misguided tribute to you, the Emperor. However, this fucking sucked!\n\nSo I made Bounce. It was a very, very complicated script package that did a few things. Firstly, if a ship was too close to another ship, it would do a 180 and fly away. Secondly, if there were no enemies about, it would make ships invincible, so they wouldn`t run into asteroids. This shit all sounds simple, but it was difficult. To attain the dimensions of where and when a ship should do that 180, users needed a wall file. That was a process, and a true test of intelligence for the Egosoft community \\(few passed\). It didn`t work as perfectly as I would have hoped for a lot of people. Mainly because people can`t read, but also because I don`t write very well, and the process was cumbersome.\n\n\033OShut Up, Litcube. What Is Bounce in LU?\033X\n\nBounce in LU is simpler for you, the player. It`s on by default in the game options menu. There`s a few differences between the old script one and this one. The biggest, is that LU Bounce is *only* a system where ships will turn around when about to collide, and that`s all it does. Here are some others:\n\nThe old Bounce uses scripts. LU Bounce does not.\nThe old Bounce guessed where to fly if it was about to have a collision. The LU bounce uses an ancient Persian magic called mathematics to ascertain the trajectory in which it should travel. You`ll see far less collisions this way.\nBounce now works on AI ships as well as player ships.\nThe thing where the old bounce would make your ships invincible when there were no enemies in sight, that thing doesn`t happen anymore. There`s no invincible bullshit anymore.\nBounce is faster. You can turn it off if you`re a crazy, but essentially, there`s negligible performance impact.</t>
 <t id="3">Carrier Command Software Update</t>
 <t id="4">Carrier Command Software has now been re-purposed. It gains new commands and assists launching and docking.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nThe carrier command software now enables a carrier to quickly dock incoming fighters. When an incoming fighter gets within a certain range \\(roughly 5k\), the ship is teleported to the carrier with a jump effect.\n\nCCS`s docking feature only works on huge ships \\(M7 and up\).\n\nIn addition to the docking feature, the software opens up a command called Carrier Command, allowing the quick action on all homebased fighters.\n\nHomebased ships will only be actioned if it has the appropriate upgrades for the requested command, reflected in the available column of the menu.</t>
 <t id="5">Complex Management</t>
 <t id="6">Vanilla complexes can be managed with a set of commands and Station Agents.\n\n\033OIntro\033X\n\nThis page is for vanilla style complexes, and not the Saturn Complex Hubs. Just a few features to make your life easier when managing them at the same time as you`re using Station Agents and Couriers.\n\n\033OSet Station Product\033X\n\nSet station product does exactly as it says. The command can only be run on a complex hub, and allows you to set the products of the station. You can remove products as well, as long as they are a resource already.\n\n\033OStation Parameters\033X\n\nA station parameter exists that allows you to set intermediates to buy, sell, buy &amp; sell, or none.\n\nThe Station Agent respects these.\n\n\033OScenario:\033X You want your homebase to buy resources and intermediates, but not sell them. Also sell products:\n\nAdd the products you want to sell using the Set Station Product command\nSet intermediates to `buy` in station parameters</t>
 <t id="7">Courier</t>
 <t id="8">The catch all of your empire, these ships can be setup with a list of destinations to pick up and drop off wares.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nThe courier has the ability to follow through with a user set delivery list. It has the capability to load and unload, with specified amounts of wares at any destination owned by you. For ships with which the courier cannot dock, it will use a transporter device to both load and unload wares. The task type &quot;loop&quot; is optional and can be put anywhere on the courier`s list; however, any delivery items below the loop would never be executed.\n\nThe courier ignores certain errors that would stop other commands in their tracks. For example, it ignores error -105, no wares available in cargo. This is going to happen a lot with the courier, because you may also be transporting with the destination points. Again, the emphasis is on the loop. If there were no wares this time around, maybe next time. Think of the courier as your galactic janitor and delivery man who just don`t give a fuck.\n\nKeep in mind it`s not the courier`s job to buy or sell; there are other software commands for that. The courier is intended to fill gaps in your trade network when you need specific wares repeatedly \\(using the &quot;loop&quot; type\) to keep up supply.\n\n\033OCourier Tasks\033X\n\nSeven tasks can be added to a Courier`s queue:\n\n\033GLoad:\033X Transfers the set number of the selected ware from the set source to the Courier. If the set number of wares is not available, it will take whatever amount the source has and move on to the next task.\n\033GFill:\033X Transfers wares from the source to the Courier until the cargo bay contains the set amount. If there are not enough wares in the source to reach this amount, the Courier will wait until there are. The next task will not begin until the Courier`s cargo bay contains the set number of wares. If the Courier already has the set amount, this task will be skipped.\n\033GUnload:\033X Transfers the set number of the selected ware from the set Courier to the set destination. If the set number of wares is not available in the Courier`s cargo bay, it will transfer as many as it has and move on to the next task.\n\033GStock:\033X Transfers wares from the Courier to the set destination until the destination contains the set amount. If the set number of wares is not available in the Courier`s cargo bay, it will transfer as many as it has and move on to the next task. If the destination already has the set amount or more than the set amount, this task will be skipped.\n\033GMaintain:\033X Transfers wares from the Courier to the set destination until the destination contains the set amount. If the set number of wares is not available in the Courier, it will transfer as many as it has and move on to the next instruction. If the destination has more than the set amount, the excess wares will be transferred to the Courier. If the destination already has the set amount, this task will be skipped.\n\033GReturn Home:\033X Instructs the Courier to dock at it`s homebase.\n\033GLoop \033X- Restarts the task queue from task #1. Note that any tasks listed after a loop task will never be done.</t>
 <t id="9">Dock Agent</t>
 <t id="10">Managing the wares by selling excess quantities set by rules of your Dockware Manager, this agent keeps your stores in check.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nThe Dock Agent`s primary purpose is to sell stuff from its homebase dock. As for the agent itself, there is very little in the way of configuration. Instead, the Dock Agent uses the Dockware Manager settings of its dock as a guideline for what to sell, utilizing capacities, overstock, and assigned wares.\n\nWhen you first start the Dock Agent command, you`ll be asked whether it will be assigned the mode sell or buy. Depending on the mode, this agent will sell goods from it`s homebase equipment dock that are not set for capacity; sell wares that exceed the set capacity; and buy any items set to buy \\(up to capacity\).\n\nDue to the agent`s requirement to coordinate between its homebased co-workers, only a total of 4 Dock Agents can be buying for a dock at a time. Selling, however has no limit. Dock agents will not waste their time selling wares worth less then 20,000 credits.\n\nSee \033YDockware Manager\033X for more information.</t>
 <t id="11">Dockware Manager 1</t>
 <t id="12">A software system for use with your empire`s equipment docks. It sets limits on wares you own and offers tools for outfitting ships.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nDockware Manager helps you organize the wares at your dock, and lets your various types of traders know what you want to keep, what you need to sell, and what to stock at the dock. It also has features for easily single-click equipping your \\(hundreds\)of ships through templates, and purchasing/equipping equipment upgrades and tuning upgrades.\n\nThere`s a number of different traders you`ll come to employ. The Dockware Manager works with two of them; the Dock Agent and Freighter. When you stock wares in your dock, as you would vanilla, the vanilla system automatically adds a ware entry to your dock, as you`ll see in the Info menu of the dock itself. Even when you remove these wares, the entry still exists, even if you want it to go away.\n\nThe command can be accessed through the context menu on the dock itself. Either through the sector map or the property menu. When you launch it, you`re presented with the first page capacities. There`s three pages in total: capacities, sources, thresholds.\n\nThe Dockware Manager allows the management of this system. Through the three pages listed above, you`ll be able to assign wares to the dock that you want to keep.\n\n\033OPage: Capacities\033X\n\nThe capacities page`s main function is to enable you to set the amount of wares you`d like to keep at your dock. From here, you can also add wares that you`re not yet tracking, and also add groups of wares that you don`t have in your hold yet.\n\nA fresh dock has no wares to track. If you load wares from a docked ship to the dock, and then open Dockware Manager, you`ll see that ware as unassigned. If you select it, it will be added to the Dockware Manager in a predefined category such as weapons, shields, missile, or ship production components \\(components required by the HQ to produce ships\). If you click on an added ware, it will be removed from the dock \\(added to unassigned\). An assigned ware shows the current amount, capacity of the ware \\(to be followed by your trade ships\), the percentage \\(stock over capacity\), and the source of the ware, if set.\n\nHighlighting an added ware and using arrow keys left and right, you`re able to set the capacity of the ware. This capacity is the amount to which your Dock Agent pilots or Freighter pilots will adhere to when stocking the dock. Any amount over this capacity will be sold by your dock agent. Your Freighters will also not ferry any more than your capacity from the wares sources. More on this later.\n\nIf you want to set the capacity of an entire group of wares, first select the desired ware group. Highlight the set group capacity option. Now use the arrows or keypad to set the desired capacity for the group \\(like the vanilla trade menu\). Hit enter, and the entire group of wares is added to your Dockware Manager at the chosen capacity.\n\n\033OPage: Sources\033X\n\nThe sources page allows you to set optional sources for your added wares. You can have Freighters ferry wares from a source to your dock. In order for your Freighter to know from where to ferry these wares, highlight the ware, and select its source. In the above image, you`ll see that Meatsteak Cahoonas has a source; it`s set to Saturn CH 20 Meatsteak. As that Saturn Complex hub pumps out Meatsteak Cahoonas, your freighter will bring them to the dock.\n\nYou can also set a source to buy. This will tell your Dock Agent that these wares should be purchased. The Dock Agent will respect the prices in your dock`s adjust station parameters menu. Make sure your dock has the required funds for these purchases.\n</t>
 <t id="13">Dockware Manager 2</t>
 <t id="14">\033OPage: Thresholds\033X\n\nAn example of the Dockware Manager`s thresholds display\n\nThe thresholds page allows you to set the minimum amount in stock at a source before the Freighter will bother going to grab stock. In the image above, you`ll see that High Energy Plasma Throwers are set to 10%. The Freighter will only go for more when the source station \\(which happens to be another Saturn Complex Hub 20x\) is at 10% capacity or higher. This function was introduced to ensure slow producing stations don`t make for unnecessary trade runs by your Freighters.\n\nWhen a ware is set to overstock, Freighters will continue to stock the ware despite the capacity settings. Additionally, Dock Agents will not sell wares set to overstock.\n\nThe top portion of the menu has other options that are helpful for outfitting your ships using all these wares you`re stocking.\n\n\033OFunction: Order Licensing\033X\n\nDockware Manager`s menu where licencing is ordered\n\nFrom this menu, you can order equipment, software, and tunings. Once purchased \\(green\), you`ll be able to equip ships with these upgrades through the upgrade ship menu. In the example image above, you can see that this dock has purchased Best Buys Locator, Cargo Bay Extension and Fight Command Software MK1, among others. Docked ships can now have these wares installed from here. Licenses are purchased on a per dock basis.\n\nLicences are specific to the dock at which they are purchased and are not transferable to other docks.\n\n\033OFunction: Template Outfit\033X\n\nTemplate outfit menu of the Dockware Manager\n\nThis function will enable you to outfit ships with your previously stored templates using the Template Manager.\n\nTemplate: Select the previously stored template you wish to use to equip the selected ships with.\nFilter Matching shiptype: Only show ships that match the shiptype in the selected template.\nFilter outfitted ships: Only show ships that have not been outfitted with the selected template.\nHide from property menu when equipped: An option that will set the ship to hide from property menu to yes once equipped with the template.\nAssign home and send: Selecting a station with this value switch will, upon equipping the ship, set that ship`s home base and send it to the selected station.\n\n</t>
 <t id="15">Dockware Manager 3</t>
 <t id="16">\033OShip List\033X \n\n\n\n\n\nYou`ll see a list of ships here. To equip a ship with the selected template, you just have to click it \\(or highlight and hit enter\). The list is colour coded: \n\n\n\n\n\n\033GGreen:\033X It`s ready to be outfitted with the selected template, you have all the wares required to outfit with the selected template. \n\n\n\033BBlue:\033X It`s been equipped with the selected template. \n\n\n\033YYellow:\033X This ship has all the wares as specified in the selected template, however, one of the configuration options doesn`t match the template spec. For example, turret commands, autojump, etc. \n\n\n\033WWhite:\033X Your dock doesn`t have the required wares to equip this ship with the selected template. \n\n\n\n\n\nProvided they are licensed by your dock, all upgrades such as software and tunings are purchased using dock funds at the time of equipping through this menu. \n\n\n\n\n\n\033OFunction: Upgrade Ship\033X \n\n\n\n\n\nA shot of Dockware Manager`s upgrade menu for ships \n\n\n\n\n\nAs you`ve seen, through the order licensing function, you`re able to purchase licenses for this dock. Using the upgrade ship menu will allow you to install those wares onto your docked ships. In the example image above, you`ll see there`s two ships docked. The Nova is selected, and the menu shows that Remote System Control Software was just installed onto the ship. \n\n\n\n\n\n\033ODockware Manager &amp; the MLCC\033X \n\n\n\n\n\nNote that a dock with the MLCC installed renders you unable to manipulate some functionality of the Dockware Manager. This is very intentional. The MLCC will automatically handle all wares through the Dockware Manager, though you do have the ability to assign sources to the automatically added wares. See: \033YMLCC\033X</t>
 <t id="17">Emergency Jump</t>
 <t id="18">Emergency Jump functions more reliably than in the vanilla version. LU comes with new technology to enhance Emergency Jump functionality.\n\n\033OIntro\n\033X \nIn my opinion, the emergency jump command in vanilla didn`t work very well.\n\nEmergency jumping in Litcube`s Universe works differently than vanilla, even without any special equipment like the Emergency Retreat Drive installed.\n\nFirstly, the ship *will* jump if its shields get below the threshold you`ve set in the Command Console. Doesn`t matter what its doing, or where it is, it will jump. The emergency jump will interrupt and override the currently running command, so use with care.\n\n\033OEmergency Retreat Drive\033X\n\nThe Emergency Retreat Drive is an expensive piece of equipment that will enable your ships to emergency jump within seconds. The emergency jump itself, when used in this manner, requires fuel in the form of Jumpdrive cores. These wares can be bought in various parts of the galaxy \\(and can be made by specific player owned factories\).\n\nWithout Jumpdrive Cores, a Jumpdrive wouldn`t be able to jump out nearly instantly, but it will still jump.\n\nDifferent classes of ships require different amounts of jump cores. Luckily, there`s a new ware resupply system implemented in LU that will allow you to automatically resupply cores which works in the same way as the built in functionality of resupply missiles, or energy.\n\nNote that once you engage a Jumpdrive manually, the Emergency Retreat Drive is temporarily shutdown until the manual jump finishes. This is due to some horse shit I made up.\n\nAs is the case with Emergency Jump, only big class ships can use it.\n\nProvided the correct components are installed, a hotkey can enable the player`s ship to utilize the Emergency Retreat Drive.\n\nJumpdrive Cores Required per class:\n\nTM: 6\nM8: 10\nM6: 17\nTL: 20\nM7: 45\nM1: 85\nM2: 125</t>
 <t id="19">Encyclopedia Update</t>
 <t id="20">The encyclopedia has been updated with a section to guide you through ware, class, and other requirements for all commands in the game.\n\n\033OSoftware And Equipment Commands\033X\n\nThe encyclopedia has a new category. The Software and equipment commands will show you all the commands available in the game and what is required to run them. This system is dynamic. It will add commands that are registered in the games script map \\(which was rewritten, but you don`t have to know that\) provided you use the new script commands that support this. See the script addon\setup.commands script if you`re interested.</t>
 <t id="21">Explorer Command Software</t>
 <t id="22">Explorer Command Software enables your scout ships to automatically explore the Universe and deploy an invaluable satellite network.\033C\n\n\033OFunction\n\033X \nExplorer command Software enables a few commands suitable for a scout ship. These commands were developed with the aim of enhancing your ability to further explore the Universe.\n\n\033GExplore Universe:\033X Commands the ship to survey the current sector to map all stations, asteroids and gates. Once completed, the ship will attempt to map the next closest unknown sector via the safest path.\n\033GDeploy Satellite Network: \033XThe ship will place a configurable array of satellites within known sectors. When the definable number of stored satellites are used up, it will purchase fresh satellites and recommence placement.\n\033GScan Asteroids:\033X Sends the ship to scan asteroids throughout the Universe.\n\033GFly Through Gate\033X Does what it says on the tin.\n\nShips following these commands aim to follow safe routes where possible \\(e.g. when explorers move to sectors bordering un-mapped sectors\). Note that a safe route requires you to *know* the actual route. However, if there are no safe routes, they will take an unsafe route.\n\nThese command requirements can be found in the Encyclopedia Update. In each case, ships running this command will be auto-renamed and moved to the top of the Property Menu.</t>
 <t id="23">Export &amp; Import</t>
 <t id="24">A system used to export your empire and import it again for various reasons which could include mod error, code change patch, or testing.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nLitcube`s Universe comes packaged with the ability to export your empire including statistics \\(kills, favourite ships\), relations, property, loadouts, game time, play time, money, Phanon state, OCV state, stations, Saturn Complex Hubs, Dockware Manager info, UT/Dock Agent/Station agent levels and stats, etc., etc., etc. Once you have exported, you can import your game into a fresh Universe.\n\nIt will not export data that was implemented by third party scripts, unless those third party scripts implement an EI extension module.\n\nAntivirus programs can significantly slow down the export process. In a test I ran, with MSE real-time protection running, export took 18 minutes. With it off, 7 seconds.\n\nIn order for this feature to function, you require the EI package installed on the downloads page.\n\n\033OWhy Would I Want To Do This?\033X\n\nDon`t do it if you don`t need to, but here`s some reasons why you would:\n\nYou installed a script, and it screwed up your game\nYou removed a script, but want to remove all traces of it\nA Patch is released and the patch said &quot;export/import required&quot;\nA Patch is released which as a different &quot;Code Base&quot; name then the one you have installed previously.\n\n\n\033OHow to Export\n\033X\nMake sure your marines are all on board ships. Don`t leave them on stations.\nWait for all Headquarter queues \\(repair, recycle, production\) to finish.\nExport your game by selecting &quot;Export empire&quot; in the Player Console \\(hotkey found in &quot;Interface&quot; in controls menu\)\nThis can take a few minutes. You can watch your log file increase in size if you`re looking at it in windows explorer \\(addon	\).\nWhen the export is finished, you`ll see the message &quot;Export Done!&quot; on your screen.\n\n\n\033OHow to Import\033X\n\nChoose New Game from the main menu.\nChoose the Damyath Import start.\n\n\nA few versions ago, LU implemented auto starting on a lot of scripts. As far as I know, I did most of them. This means that if you`re playing LU, all of your stuff should have auto started, so you won`t have to run the UT command, for example. Check your stuff anyway, in case you`re running mods.</t>
 <t id="25">FLC</t>
 <t id="26">Whenever your ship or ships you own destroy an enemy, they leave behind cargo. This loot increases with your fight rank.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nF.L.C. stands for Fightrank Loot Chance. It`s demonstrated as a percentage, which is the chance that an item on a ship will be dropped in a container as opposed to being destroyed with the ship.\n\nThis chance is checked per component on the ship. So if you just popped a pirate M5 that had 6 IREs, and your FLC is 1.2%, there`s a 1.2% chance for `each` IRE that it`ll be dropped as loot.\n\nThis new rule comes into effect with anything you or your owned ships kill, in sector or out of sector.\n\n\nKeep in mind:\n\nIn-game, FLC doesn`t go above a visible amount until level 19 @ 15%</t>
 <t id="27">Freighter</t>
 <t id="28">Used to ferry wares to and from sources to docks by following rules setup by your Dockware Manager.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nA simple command, the Freighter is designed to work with your dock and the dock`s source stations. Freighters should be homebased to a dock. Once the command is run, they`ll use your Dockware Manager`s source information to figure out where to get wares required for the dock. See the sources section of Dockware Manager.\n\nThey`ll also pay attention to threshold limits on those specified sources so that your freighters aren`t making multiple runs, wasting fuel, just to pick up a few wares. See the thresholds section of Dockware Manager.\n\nA ware set to overstock will enable the Freighter to continue stocking well past its home dock`s capacity limit.\n\nFreighters do not buy wares for those wares set to buy. Dock Agent does.\n\nFreighter command requirements can be found in the Encyclopedia</t>
 <t id="29">GoD Changes</t>
 <t id="30">How ships, stations, and other objects spawn in the Universe has changed slightly.\n\n\033OChanges\033X\n\nA few changes you might notice about the game`s galaxy engine:\n\nShips no longer spawn out of thin air. They will spawn only in their respective race`s shipyards.\nTLs will build stations anywhere in the universe, but they do need to travel there.\nJobs now pick from all ship variants\nIf the ship isn`t a job shop, GoD will not spawn it\nShipyards, Docks, OWPs still spawn, but not if the sector is taken over by an aggressive race \\(Kha`ak, OCV, Xenon\)\n\nThe jobs engine has also been rewritten, with a few added benefits. All variants of ships are chosen. In vanilla, only the first found ship with a matching variant was used, even if the race has several variants within the same class.</t>
 <t id="31">Hotkeys</t>
 <t id="32">Hotkeys help you do things faster when you need them quick. There`s lots of them in Litcube`s Universe.\n\nHotkeys may be found and set within the vanilla and extension sections of Controls Menu.</t>
 <t id="33">MLCC About</t>
 <t id="34">Use the Military Logistics Command Center to organize your fleets. Design and plan specific orders for your ships to follow in an engagement.\n\n\033OWhat is it?\033X\n\nThe MLCC is a system providing you a whole suite of features that enable you to automate outfitting, fuelling, rearming, calling in assists, and carrying out predefined attack strategies.\n\nTo use the MLCC, you require a dock owned by you. You install the MLCC suite through the commands menu on the dock itself. After that, you`re able to bring up the MLCC set up menu which is hotkey initiated.\n\n\033OInstallation\033X\n\nStarting off, MLCC needs to be installed into a dock. This is done through the station`s command menu, where a small fee is charged. At first, you`ll likely only have one dock, as your fledgling fleet is small enough to fit on a single dock. As you grow, however, you`ll probably purchase more docks. MLCC needs to be installed on each dock where you have your military ships. It`s not a good idea to install MLCC on your headquarters. A dock with MLCC installed onto it is considered an MLCC dock.\n\nIn order for your ships to be included as MLCC ships, they need to be assigned to an MLCC dock by way of homebase. Assign the ship`s homebase as an MLCC dock, and it will be included in all future MLCC menus. There aren`t separate MLCC menus for each MLCC dock. All MLCC docks act as a network; all ships stationed at all MLCC docks will be included in the menus \\(i.e. configuration, assist, sortie\).\n\nThe MLCC will handle your Dockware management from here on out, and as such, you cannot change Dockware Manager settings on an MLCC dock. The only wares that will be added to the Dockware Manager are wares your ships use. Obviously ships have to be homebased to the MLCC dock in order for them to be managed \\(as with every other MLCC feature\). You still have the option for using sources within the Dockware Manager so that you can assign Freighters to ensure your MLCC dock is stocked for the dock`s fleet. See: Dockware Manager\n\n\033OFunctionality &amp; Orders\033X\n\nOnce you have an MLCC dock with your military ships assigned, you will be able to set various rules for how your fleets are auto managed. There`s four main parts:\n\nIntercept\nShip Assist Rules of Engagement\nHangars\nMissile Rules of Engagement\n\nIn order for the MLCC to have any functionality at all, you`ll need to have ships assigned to the MLCC. The assigned ships are intended to be of class M6 or larger. Fighter capability is intended to be in the form of carrier wings, which should be homebased to a carrier, and the carrier, in turn, homebased to the MLCC.\n\n\033CMLCC Main Menu\033X\n\nActivated by hotkey only, this is the root of all MLCC menus. From here, you can navigate to the main functions of the MLCC suite of commands.</t>
 <t id="35">MLCC Configuration</t>
 <t id="36">\033CConfiguration Menu\033X\n\nThe first thing you`ll need to do after installing the MLCC on a dock for the first time, is to dock a military ship you`d like to hand over to MLCC control. Assign the MLCC dock as the ship`s homebase, and you`ll be allowed to configure the ship `type` in the configuration menu.\n\nThis thing fields the configuration of ship assist rules of engagement and missile rules of engagement. Note how they`e two different things. You can also view your hangar settings from here. There`s four sections here, as you can see.\n\nThe top section gives you a snapshot of the ship types that you have configured for MLCC use showing interception toggle as well as primary, secondary, tertiary, and final orders. You can select a ship type from this section to edit a previously configured ship type.\n\nThe second section shows ship types that are unassigned, or not yet configured. You can select one to enter the configuration screen.\n\nThe third section allows you to setup hangars for those configured ship types that can hangar ships.\n\nThe final section allows you to add and modify missile rules of engagement.\n\n\033CShip Assist Rules Of Engagement Configuration\n\033X \nTo get to this menu, select a ship type from either the MLCC Configuration menu`s first or second section.\n\nAny ship type that has a homebase set to an MLCC enabled dock will show up in this menu. Here, you can configure 4 stages of orders. The stages are simply the sequence in which orders are executed. Each stage can be assigned an order of: Assault, Carrier, Retreat, Bomber, and Escort.\n\nEach of those orders has configuration options. For example assault: only engage fighters, or only engage capital ships. Or for the carrier order, how many per wing to attack, and what to attack, how many losses can this ship type incur before retreating.\n\nScenario for above config: You`re in an OCV sector. There`s about 60 enemy ships. You are alone. But you have your fleet stationed at your MLCC docks fuelled and ready. You bring up your MLCC main menu, and call an assist. Your MLCC ships know what that means: they jump to you immediately. But not in a large mass. In an organized wall facing the same direction you are \\(that took a lot of math\).\n\nThe recent arrivals will wait in this wall formation until you give the go code hotkey. You wait for the right moment to unleash hell.\n\nYou hit the MLCC go code hotkey. Your ships launch into action, all executing your pre-coded orders.\n\nFor example, your 16 Heavy Centaur Prototypes set in the example above will immediately start searching for capital ships \\(primary order\). When none are left, they will attack fighters \\(secondary order\). Then they will attack capitals again \\(tertiary order\), in case any stragglers show up in scanner range. They then will fly to you, and protect your ship \\(final order\).</t>
 <t id="37">MLCC Orders &amp; Hangars</t>
 <t id="38">\033OAssistance\033X\n\nThis menu is reached from MLCC`s main menu. Calling for assistance is likely one of the first orders you`ll issue your MLCC ships. The command essentially calls your MLCC ships to assist you in battle and execute their orders. The menu shows a few options. The first two items are rally options depicting the behaviour of how the MLCC ships will get to you. The rest are sliders you can use to include or exclude the ship types from the assist call, which you`ll need to set prior to hitting a rally option.\n\nRally: standard: Ships will use normal autojump settings to get to you, jumping to the nearest available point\nRally: jump beacon: If your ship has a jump beacon on board, the MLCC ships will use it. The jump beacon doesn`t need to be deployed. The resulting jump in creates a giant wall formation in front of your ship, evenly spaced out, and all facing the same direction as you are, ready and waiting for your go code.\nSelection group: The currently selected assist group that will rally. This selection is previously saved using `copy to new group`\nCopy to new group: Saves the current grouping to a selection group\nDelete current group: Deletes the currently selected group\n\nYour ships will respond to the assistance call by jumping in to your sector \(in a manner specified by the rally option\). Once there, they will wait until you hit the MLCC go code to start executing their assistance rules of engagement.\n\n\033OIntercept\033X\n\nYou might not know it, but your Universal Traders are always logging complains about the inability to fulfill lucrative transactions due to the presence of sector threats. Every time a UT attempts to make a deal where there is an enemy that could cause trouble, the UT logs the complaint and moves on to another opportunity. You can view this complaint log by selecting `sector security complaints` in your player console.\n\nIntercept is a single command accessed through the MLCC main menu. When you run an intercept sortie, all of your MLCC ship that are assigned a yes to interceptions their in their ship type`s configuration, will jump to handle these security complaints that were registered by your UTs.\n\nThey will be smart. There`s math involved to ensure they stand a very good chance of wining the ensuing battle with the targets they choose. They will smart jump; if the enemy is headed toward a gate, they`ll jump to the enemy`s targeted gate to intercept.\n\nCheck your logbook after an intercept order is given to see the status.\n\n\033OHangars\033X\n\nThe hangar in question is a station that really does nothing but station fighter wings. It is important to note that the hangar is not an MLCC station, and does not require MLCC to be installed to function as a hangar. It is referenced in the MLCC menu in the ship type configuration \(as per the Emeus config example image above\). The hangar section of the MLCC menu is basically a list of two fields:\n\nWhat hanger?\nWhat ships are stored here?\n\nThe first field is simply a station where your fighters are docked, and for obvious reasons, it`s a good idea to have the hangar in the same safe sector that your carrier`s MLCC is setup. The latter field is a template entry. The ships in this hangar are probably going to be labelled Reserve \(which would have been done when you mass equipped them at a dock, see: Dockware Manager\). Templates are set in the Template Manager.</t>
 <t id="39">MLCC Missile Rules of Engagement\n</t>
 <t id="40">\033OMissile Rules of Engagement \(RoE\):\033X\n\nI found vanilla missile engagement lame. During an MLCC ship`s execution of orders, you can set missile rules of engagement. It`s important to note that these rules will only effect ships that call an MLCC home, and are currently executing their automated orders. As soon as you intervene in orders, they will cease to use these rules.\n\nThe missile rules are basically as follows:\n\nMissile Type\nTarget Type\nRange\nFire Rate\n\nUsing an example of Air to Air Asps, we`d need a quick missile. 16 Wildfires would do. So we go into our MLCC main menu, and Add a new missile ROE. The first field being the ship type that follows this rule. We`d use the filters on the main configuration menu, maker race \(Split\), then class \(M4\), then select Asp. and hit &quot;New&quot; in the Missile ROE section.\n\nThe Missile RoE for all Asps now shows. We`ll add the wildfire missile, because that`s what we`ll be using.\n\nNow we have to set what type of targets the wildfire should fire at.\n\nAdd fighters. Set the range to between 1,500m and 8,000m. Frequency 80%.\n\nAdd M2 to the wildfire \(for lulz\), set range to between to 10,000m and 25,000m. Frequency 20%\n\nSo now when our asps are in the field, if they see fighters, there`s an 80% chance every 5 seconds they will fire a wildfire at a nearby enemy fighter if it is within the range of between 1,500m and 8,000m.\n\nAlso, if there`s an M2 within 10,000m and 25,000m, it will fire a wildfire 20% of the time.\n\nYou can add as many target RoEs, per as many missiles, per as many ship types as you want.\n\nI found Discoverers loaded with fireflies attacking an M2 to be devastating. Expensive as hell, but devastating.</t>
 <t id="41">Missile Defense</t>
 <t id="42">Chaff is a new missile countermeasure used by all ships. M8s use them to an effective degree.\n\n\033OIntroduction\033X\n\nMissile defense is a new system in LU designed around the &quot;chaff&quot; which is a re purposed mosquito missile. All ships have the ability to fire chaff. There is a hotkey available to the player to launch chaff when there`s an incoming missile. Once launched, the chaff is nearly always successful at intercepting enemy missiles.\n\n\033OMissile Boats\033X\n\nTo add a little value to M8 class ships, when an M8`s missile turret is set to Missiles Only, it will monitor all ships \(of the same race\) within the chaff`s range, which is about 20 km.\n\nIf any missiles are targeting a monitored ship, the M8 will fire a chaff at the incoming missile. Chaff are no ordinary missiles; they`re lightning quick, and carry a very generous proximity fuse. Any missile that comes within a few hundred meters of a chaff is destroyed.\n\nAs an added benefit to the upgraded chaff missile, when fired, they will target the nearest incoming missile, regardless of current target.\n\nNote that only one turret per M8 really requires Missiles Only to be set, leaving the other turret for attacking.\n\n\033OChaff Countermeasure Defense System\033X\n\nCCDS is a ship system that enables auto firing of chaff at incoming missiles. There is no configuration required beyond equipping the ship with chaff, and of course having the respective CCDS system installed on the ship. If the system is installed, the ship will track incoming missiles and fire chaff.\n\nThere are 3 variants; MK1, MK2, MK3.\n\nThe only difference between the three systems is who manufactures them, and in turn where they are purchased, and also the success rate the system has at intercepting the incoming missiles.\n\nThere is a random variable in the form of the pilot`s flight skill, but other than that, the CCDS can intercept roughly 77%, 89%, 100% of incoming missiles for MK1, MK2, and MK3 variants respectively.\n\nInstalling this on a player ship is only useful if you don`t plan on mapping your &quot;fire chaff&quot; hotkey like an idiot. If you don`t do it, because you`re a giant fool, you can install a CCDS and have the CCDS do the firing for you, with the standard interception chances.</t>
 <t id="43">Mobile Mining</t>
 <t id="44">Mobile Mining is a completely new system in LU which completely replaces the vanilla version. New ships, lasers, and commands.\n\n\033OIntroduction\033X\n\nHere`s the quick and dirty. The Mobile Drilling System and Ore Collector have been re-purposed. Hit a rock with your MDS, and you have a chance of your ore collector popping something into your cargo bay. It`s as simple as that. Care was taken to ensure that the efficiency of miners was the same out of sector as it would be in sector.\n\n\033OMobile Drilling System Is Different\033X\n\nHitting a debris rock with the MDS is now the only way to mine. When the debris rock is hit, there is a chance for a mineral or crystal to be &quot;loosened&quot;. The Ore Collector will beam the loosened material into the cargo bay, which all happens automatically. Depending on the rock size, it can only take so many hits before breaking apart. The larger the debris rock, the more hits it can take. Larger debris rocks will break into smaller debris rocks. The calculation is performed every time a laser bullet hits a rock; so yes, the more lasers, the faster the mining.\n\nOnly the new miner variant of ships can actually equip MDS lasers.\n\nNOTE: You must install Mobile Drilling Systems in all compatible slots for the mining commands to work. For example, if you got Chimera Miners you need to fill all eight of the main weapon slots with MDS lasers, otherwise the mining commands will be unavailable.\n\n\033ORare Minerals and Crystals\033X\n\nSome of the time when you hit a rock, you`ll get a mineral like ore, silicon, ice, or nividium. Rarely, you`ll end up with a rare mineral or crystal.\n\nUpon an MDS hitting, the ship has a chance of loosening a material. If something is loosened, it could be a resource ware, a rare mineral, or crystal. Note that small variations in percentages are based on the type of debris. Ice has a slightly higher chance of yielding crystal, and Nividium has a slightly higher chance of yielding both rare minerals and crystals.\n\n\033OMining Outposts\033X\n\nPlutarch, NMMC, Pirates, and the USC have all setup Mining Outposts stationed throughout the Universe. They`ll buy mineral resources, rare minerals, and crystals. Rare Minerals and Crystals will be consumed at these docks at a far quicker pace than other wares would be.</t>
 <t id="45">Omicron Channel Virus \(OCV\)</t>
 <t id="46">The OCV are an emerging threat in the far East of the galaxy.\n\n\033OThe OCV\033X\n\nAt some distant part of the Universe, something is making the commonwealth governments uneasy. There`s a new threat, and it`s encroaching on the Galaxy.\n\nA new channel of sectors was discovered East of Bluish Snout. These sectors were named the Omicron Channel, whose ownership was divided among the commonwealth races. Trade was established, citizens pioneered the new frontier, and it looked as though a new era of peace was to settle upon this new discovery.\n\nIt wasn`t long, however, until the true nature of the Omicron Channel was revealed.\n\nAt the end of the channel, lies a brewing enemy. The Omicron Channel Virus, as it`s called, is a menacing threat to the entire galaxy. As their fleets expand with incredibly resilient and deadly ships not found in any other parts of the Universe, they will take over sectors, and establish new fronts. The rate of expansion provides a challenge, without becoming a frantic race against the clock.\n\n\033GPossible Spoilers:\033X\n\nThere rate of expansion is roughly one sector per few hours at first. The time for sector take over relies on their ability to ferry resources from their home sector \(deep in the channel\), to their new territory. Therefore, their rate of expansion slows exponentially the further the sector is away from their home sector. That being said, the 10 sector channel can be conquered by the OCV within 3 to 4 game days, at which point they`ll breach Bluish Snout and continue their rampage.\n\n\033GEnd Possible Spoilers\033X\n</t>
 <t id="47">Pathfinding</t>
 <t id="48">Some ship commands make use of the ability to traverse the Universe without flying through hostile sectors.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nDon`t you hate it when you just bought a ship in Queens Harbour, and it needs to get to Argon Prime, you send it on its way, and you have to baby sit it to ensure it doesn`t fly through Xenon or Pirate sectors?\n\nSector pathfinding is implemented in every facet of the game now. When using the Navigation Command Software Mk1, you can use commands to &quot;fly safe&quot;, which enables the ship to avoid all sectors that the ship has set to foe.\n\nTraders who don`t have a jump drive \(Station Agent, Dock Trader, UT, Freighter, etc.\) search for close trades based on flying safe. In other words, if there`s a good trade on the other side of Farnham`s Legend that seems lucrative and closer, and your jump-less trader chooses one a few sectors away instead, consider that the path to the first trade was longer, considering it had to avoid Farnham`s Legend, a pirate sector, to get to that destination.\n\nOther jump-less scripts also use foe pathfinding, such as deploy satellites.\n\nIn the image below, you can see a ship`s navigation menu with the Navigation Command Software Mk1 installed, illustrating the fly safe commands.</t>
 <t id="49">Phanon Corperation</t>
 <t id="50">Phanon Corporation is a competing corporation in LU. They trade, fight, think, and build just like you do.\n\n\033OHey, I remember this!\033X\n\nYou may remember in the Egosoft forums that The Phanon Corporation was a script package that introduced a competing faction that bought traders, military, and stations in an effort to expand their empire. It was mildly popular, bug reports were essentially non-existent, and performance was surprisingly good.\n\nMy goal in creating this plugin was to create some life in the Universe that carried on with out you, reacting to the game state. I also have a passion for performance, and paid close attention to the impact that this script might have on other factors in the Universe. I can avoid loop checks by storing pertinent information in arrays, and save script cycles by using priority sequence step timing \(non-important tasks only checked once every 5 mins, etc.\). Many years of testing went into this so far.\n\nThis AL Plugin can represent a challenge, especially in later levels, as The Phanon Corporation will steal trade opportunities, and actively hunt and destroy your ships and factories with M6 / M7 led fleets. As they gain more money, they will purchase capital ships to guard their HQ. Especially in later generations, the HQ can be difficult to destroy, as the sector will be well fortified.\n\nIf you want quick action, this script isn`t for you; it was intended to be started at the same time as a player as a means to incite the player to get moving on creating his empire. Because if you don`t, The Phanon Corporation will. And eventually, they will take over; but at a non-cheating pace. It can take just as much time for The Phanon Corporation`s subsidiaries to build an empire as a player in the early generations. However, disturb them \(kill their corvettes, cap their traders\), and this progress will obviously slow.\n\nIt`s been mentioned that the Phanon Corporation start out with a cash injection that is larger than the player`s. This is true. If the Phanon started with a single M5 and 3,000 credits, it`d be a pretty anti-climactic game-play element. Until I can implement multiple corporations, the Phanon Corporation will have to start out with an advantage.\n\n\033OWhat`s The Phanon Corporation Like in LU?\033X\n\nThis plugin creates a new enemy faction, The Phanon Corporation, that is far more aggressive in its monopolization efforts than any existing known company \(NNMC, Duke`s, etc.\)\n\nEverything The Phanon Corporation buys, it pays for\nIt will not purchase anything if it doesn`t have the funds required\nBuys stations, traders, headquarters, fighters, capital ships\nMaintains a proper fleet ratio \(i.e. X number of m5s to m2s\)</t>
 <t id="51">Plutarch Tractor System</t>
 <t id="52">Move asteroids across the Universe with this new technology.\n\n\033OBackground\n\033X\nThe Teladi, well known for manipulating trade sector station and gate arrangements to increase trade profits, have recently assisted in the development of a highly capable device to further the trend. The development was a joint contract, with research assistance from the Plutarch Mining Corporation`s research division and NMMC`s capable funding capital. Due to maintaining most of the logistics control throughout the duration of the project, Plutarch was able to win the brand name on the technology with surprisingly little negotiation. The Plutarch Tractor System is a technology that allows the ship to instantly jump an entire asteroid to known coordinates. Through calibration of tractor beam technology and small expendable jump drives the tractor system is capable of sending the asteroid to any point in the known Universe. A notable application of the system is a precise amalgamation of two asteroids, essentially combining their yields. The device comes with a cost: huge amounts of quantum tubes, energy cells, and crystals are required to fabricate the large quantity of jumpdrive probes required for the procedure.\n\n\033OFunction\033X\n\nOnce a TL is equipped with the appropriate wares, a menu will be brought up with a sector and asteroid listings.\n\nEssentially, the Plutarch Tractor System offers two functions.\n\nMove: Asteroids can be moved within a sector or from entirely different sectors.\nCompact: Asteroids can be moved `into` another asteroid, effectively combining their yields.\n\n\n\033OCost\033X\n\nTo make a move with an asteroid, your TL must be loaded with enough crystals, quantum tubes, and energy cells to make the jump. The command calculates the exact distance in meters \(even between gates\).\n\nPlutarch Tractor System usage costs\nWare\t\t Cost / Meter\nEnergy Cells\t 6666.6\nCrystals\t 1666.6\nQuantum tubes\t 42.6</t>
 <t id="53">Quantum Jumpgate Extension</t>
 <t id="54">New technology allows you and your ships to jump to new points in a sector.\n\n\033ONew Jumping Features\033X\n\nThe Quantum Jumpgate Extension is sold at equipment docks throughout the galaxy. When the pricey extension is installed on your ship you have a few new jump options available in the sector map. In addition to the gates, you can now jump to jump beacons and sector centres. If you`re on good terms with a jump beacon`s race, the jump beacon becomes a jump option. The sector center is always available, provided the Quantum Jumpgate Extension is installed.\n\nAI ships will always use the closest jump point to their destination, which is why it`s a good idea to fit trader ships with a Quantum Jumpgate Extension when you can afford it. It can cut down jump times considerably, when centre sector and available jumpbeacons are available.\n\nYou can, of course, place your own jump beacons. Though prohibitively expensive, they can increase the efficiency of your trading network. Even if the beacon is owned by you, a Quantum Jumpgate Extension is still necessary to use them.</t>
 <t id="55">Quickshuttles</t>
 <t id="56">Two quick hotkey based systems for quick response to some of the most common errands when managing an empire.\n\n\033OIntroduction\033X\n\nCurrently, there`s two quickshuttles, both of which play an important role in your empire management. They each have two hotkeys: one to activate and one to send them home. It`s advisable to have jump drives on your quickshuttles; they`re not too quick without them.\n\nQuickshuttles require a homebase in order to enact their go code. It`s recommended that they be of TS class, as they require larger cargo bays.\n\nTo set your quick shuttle, use the player console.\n\n\033OFuel Quickshuttle\033X\n\nRequired ware: Transporter Device\nRequired ware: Trade Command Software Mk1\nRequired ware: Supply Command Software\n\nWhen you hit the go hotkey for this quickshuttle, your fuel quickshuttle will jump to your sector and fuel your ship. If your current target is one of your ships, it will fuel said ship instead. This command will also fuel every ship in the target ship`s group, which is defined as ships following each other. If the quickshuttle is docked at their homebase when the command is executed, it will load all energy it can from there, which will avoid the necessity of the shuttle having to purchase energy cells.\n\n\033OReap Quickshuttle\033X\n\nRequired ware: Transporter Device\nRequired ware: Special Command Software Mk1\n\nReap the rewards of your battle with the reap quickshuttle. With one hotkey press for the go command, the quickshuttle will jump into your current sector and collect all flying wares \(loot\).\n\nAs the shuttle is equipped with a transporter device, it only needs to be within transporter range of the ware before it beams it into its cargobay. If your quickshuttle minimum jumps is set to 0, it will assess the closest jump point to the next closest ware before flying; if jumping to a gate is quicker, it will jump. The reap quickshuttle can clean a sector of wares in short order using this method.\n\nOnce all wares within player property scan range have been collected, the reap quickshuttle will send you a report on what was collected, and promptly return to homebase. Once docked at homebase, the reap quickshuttle will unload its cargo if the homebase can be loaded with that particular ware.</t>
 <t id="57">Saturn Complex Hub 1</t>
 <t id="58">Build massive complexes in a compact station, using Terran technology. Easier to setup, better performance.\n\n\033OWhat is a Saturn Complex Hub?\033X\n\nEssentially, a Saturn Complex Hub is a single station, based on the Terran Crystal Fab model. Once deployed and configured correctly, it acts as a normal factory producing a single ware, with no resources required, as per a self-sustaining complex. I`ve modified the model to contain a capital dock port and 20 freighter arms. There`s 400 variations, each representing a product`s production capability, but otherwise identical. However, it`s not a cheating factory. For those wishing for a simple and easy &quot;remove resources&quot; factory, look elsewhere.\n\nBenefits:\n\nDoesn`t cheat.\nProduce the same amount of wares without the FPS bog of vanilla complexes\nNo more /!\ flashing stations; no resources required.\nNeeded factories can be automatically purchased by your TL.\nEasy to use.\n\nThe Saturn Complex Hub must be fitted with all of the stations as would a regular complex. Here`s how:\n\n\033OHow do I set up my Saturn Complex Hub?\033X\n\nFly a TL to Saturn 3. Dock at the shipyard in that sector. You`ll see a whole load of Saturn Complex Hubs for sale. The number after the sale item is the &quot;production&quot; of the module itself. As a reference, M sized factories would be the equivalent of a Saturn Complex Hub 002, and an L sized factory would be the equivalent of a Saturn Complex Hub 005. They go all the way up to 400. Once deployed from your TL`s cargo hold as you would a regular factory in a sector of your choosing \(preferably with a lot of scanned asteroids\), select the command &quot;Saturn Hub Console&quot; under the command console of the station.\n\nFrom here, you can decide which products you`d like your Saturn CH to produce. Select the default station at the bottom under &quot;Production Configuration Options&quot; to change to another station to use as the basis of the production configuration. Only stations for sale in the Universe will be available here. For example, if you`d like the Saturn CH to produce Bofu, change the station shown to a Boron BoFu Chemical Lab. Once you`re happy with your selection, select &quot;Set production configuration&quot;. As the amount of math required to figure out what stations are required is tremendous \(this script is essentially a complex calculator, as you`ve seen around these forums\), there`s a small wait \(3 seconds or so\). What you now see, is the requirement of stations to make a self-sustaining complex.</t>
 <t id="59">Saturn Complex Hub 2</t>
 <t id="60">\033OA few notes on how the math is done:\033X\n\nRequired to be a self-sustaining complex\n\nUses same race factories when possible\n\nOnly uses L sized mines \(more efficient\)\n\nMinimum energy surplus is configurable. Note, that even if the minimum is set at 0, even though the SCH will endeavour to put together the lowest overkill in terms of coverage on ware production to be self sustaining, more often than not, you`ll see a 104% - 120% energy coverage. This is normal, can`t be avoided, and it`s what you`d see with a vanilla complex, and just the way the math works, etc. As an example, if you have a big ore complex with many small cargo freighters, and you know there`s going to be a shit load of jumps made, you might want to ensure that the complex is built with a minimum energy resevoir of, say, 10,000 e-cells per hour. So when configuring the station, ensure 10,000 is set in the minimum energy reservoir field. The SCH will ensure that more energy production is included in the math. You`ll pay for it in terms of having to purchase more/larger SPP and their support factories, but it`s your call. Don`t bitch to me when your OreComplexOfMassiveness has no energy in its reservoir for your traders to jump to their destinations.. This is non-cheating, meaning the script will include more SPPs to achieve the minimum energy surplus. Sometimes a regular self sustaining complex has more energy surplus than said minimum, in which case, no extra stations above and beyond what would sustain the product ware would be required. As explain previously, energy surplus is added to the secondary resource as per regular cycle time and production. Secondary resources have absolutely no bearing on production, so don`t worry if you empty it; you`ll still produce.\n\nEnergy producing Saturn Complex Hubs ignore energy surplus \(for obvious reasons\).\n\nSuns are taken into account for SPPs. I did the math \(with help from members Smile \), to take into account suns from 50% all the way to 2000%\053 in 50% increments. So you`re safe.\n\nThe math accepts 99.85% crystal production to energy cell production as acceptable and self-sustaining. It`s a minor fudge that will save you a few credits per year.\n\n</t>
 <t id="61">Saturn Complex Hub 3</t>
 <t id="62">\033OHere`s a description of some important elements of the SCH screen:\033X\n\nReset production configuration: Goes back to the previous screen, to re-set the product of the Saturn CH. This command is unavailable if the Saturn Complex Hub contains installed stations. Also, as all of the products will be removed from the station on a production configuration reset, a docked TL is required with adequate cargo space if there is remaining ware stock in the Saturn Complex Hub.\n\nOperation: Toggle this to change the operation when you select the rows in the third pane down. Either to &quot;Install&quot; the stations in a docked TL cargo hold into the Saturn Complex Hub, or &quot;Remove&quot; the stations from the hub back into the TL.\n\nSource TL: This is the docked TL.\n\nEngage: You can`t see it now, but once you`ve installed all stations and asteroids, this command becomes available. Once selected, it starts the production of the station, and the installation panel is hidden \(below\).\n\nProduction Configuration: This shows you what`s going to be produced once the Saturn Complex Hub is engaged, how long the production cycle, how many per cycle, how many per hour \(hr\), which resources the product is based on internally, whether it`s engaged or disengaged, and energy surplus. Energy surplus is calculated, just as a regular complex would have. It represents the total produced energy, minus the energy resource required. This is necessary for your traders to sell their wares while making jumps.\n\nBlue stations \(installation panel\): This pane is the interactive panel used to install stations from your TL into the Saturn Complex Hub. Selecting a row will remove the stations from your TL, and install them into the Saturn CH. Changing the &quot;Operation&quot; will reverse this process.\n\nPurple mineral wares \(installation panel\): Some of your stations require asteroids! Selecting this will bring up an asteroid selection screen. Selecting an asteroid at this point will &quot;import&quot; the asteroid \(using built in mining drills, tractor beams, and transport devices - what do you think you paid for?\). If only a fraction of the asteroid is required, the remainder will be left. Note once an asteroid is implemented, it can be placed back onto an asteroid as long as an asteroid of the same resource type exists within the same sector.\n\nWare production panel: Gives you an idea of what`s going on inside your Saturn Complex Hub when it`s churning out wares. Figures are listed as wares per hour. You`ll note that crystal coverage is 99.58%, and apparently acceptable. That`s intentional.\n\nExtraneous Station Info: More info on stations required/installed within this hub.\n</t>
 <t id="63">Saturn Complex Hub 4</t>
 <t id="64">So as stated before, you`re going to have to fill your TL up with the required stations. Using an example of a size 020 1MJ Shield SCH, you`d need to go and purchase, 18 Cahoona Bakery M, 18 Cattle Ranch M, 8 Crystal Fab M, an Ore Mine L, 20 Shield Prod. Facility 1 MJ, a Silicon Mine L, and 8 Solar Power Plant Ms. Maker race is important here.\n\nAlternatively, you can have any owned TL do the shopping for your SCH automatically. Make sure the following conditions are met:\n\nEnough credits at your TL`s home port \(or your player account if the TL doesn`t have a homebase set\)\nTL Sized Ship\nTrade Command 1/2\nTrading System Extension\nA Jump Drive is recommended\n\nOnce the required components are installed in the TL, you can select the &quot;Shop for Saturn CH&quot; from the Trade menu, then select the Saturn Complex Hub you would like to equip \(assuring that the SCH has the required amount of money in it`s account\)and the TL will head off and quickly collect the required stations. Once the shopping is done, order the TL to dock at the SCH and you will be able to auto-fit the stations automatically from the SCH menu.\n\nOnce you`ve picked these up, dock the TL at the Saturn Complex Hub. You can then select the blue colour items to install the stations from your TL into the hub. Next, install the asteroids \(purple wares\).\n\nIf everything in this pane is green, and you see the &quot;Engage&quot;, you`re ready to produce. Hit engage, and the Saturn Complex Hub will start pumping out wares.\n\n\033OMove Logistics\033X\n\nThere`s a handy station command called move logistics that enables you to move all your station agents, trade report, and station settings to another station. This is useful for when you`re upgrading your SCH to a larger size. When you have your new one setup, run the move logistics command on the old SCH, and move logistics to the new one. All your station agents will start using the new station, station settings will be moved, and so will the trade report. Dockware manager sources will also be moved to the new station.\n</t>
 <t id="65">Ship Compendium</t>
 <t id="66">Quick and easy access to a database with which you can compare ship stats, abilities, and cost.\n\n\033OIn Game Ship Stats\033X\n\nAccessed through the player console, you can see ship statistics from all the ships sold at shipyard that you have discovered.</t>
 <t id="67">Station Agent</t>
 <t id="68">These sales agents are in charge of purchasing your factory`s resources and selling their products.\n\n\033OManage Your Stations\033X\n\nThe Station Agent software allows a ship to manage the wares of its homebase station. The ship will monitor the station`s progress and buy wares or sell them as per the station parameters import and export thresholds. Priority is given to purchasing required wares for the station.\n\nStation Agent command requirements can be found in the \033YEncyclopedia\033X</t>
 <t id="69">Stock Exchange</t>
 <t id="70">A completely new system that overrides the vanilla stock exchange system.\n\n\033OInvest Your Money\033X\n\nThe stock exchange in LU has changed, but you`re still required to unlock the individual stock exchanges just as you would in vanilla. The more stock exchanges you unlock, the more stocks you`ll have access to. Each stock exchange has its own stock listings.\n\nOnce you`ve unlocked a stock exchange, the context menu item view local stock exchange on the station itself will be enabled. The exchange that you`ve unlocked will also become available in the stock exchange menu brought up with the stock exchange hotkey. Both methods bring up the exact same menu. However, if you`re not in the same sector as the stock exchange, you`re required to have player property present in the sector in order to access that particular stock exchange.\n\nEssentially, the stock exchange is now a relatively safe investment opportunity that isn`t linked to any particular variable in the Universe. In other words, you can no longer exploit it. I just felt that, as a video game, the Universe isn`t big enough, nor are there enough variables, to make exploitation of the exchange to be anything close to a fair game play advantage. I mean, if the universe was filled with thousands of sectors with billions of wares, and you managed to exploit it, I would have kept the vanilla version. But when you can buy all stock of a ware in the entire known Universe and move from one sector to another, and call that exploiting the market...\n\nSo now, the stock exchange is random. Stocks you buy may go up, they may go down. They may go on a huge upswing, they may crash. You`ll never really know. As you gain capital and start investing, you`ll basically be buying low, selling high, and you will make a profit. The more you invest, the more you`ll profit. Probably. In time. Maybe.\n\nThe stock names, prices, capacities, quantities, variability, are all generated on a new game start. They`ll be different in every game. Different races have different types of stock values, and stock quantities. For example, Teladi are high risk/high gain, Boron are safest, you need to be fucking rich to trade in the Terran exchange.\n\nAs the menu states, you`ll pay 2% on purchases and sales of all stock. This tariff isn`t reflected in the menu slider, but it`s applied to the sale or purchase after confirmation.</t>
 <t id="71">Supply Command Software</t>
 <t id="72">Outfit your ships, bring them wares, or use templates to equip a fleet using this new software.\n\n\033OIntroduction\033X\n\nI did enjoy the vanilla version of Supply Command Software, but I felt it required a few changes. The LU version enables a few more commands that are helpful in automating the delivery of wares to your ships.\n\n\033OSupply Ships\033X\n\nIn this scenario, once activated, the ship will purchase the selected type and amount, then proceed to transport your selection to the targeted ship via transporter device. If supply entire formation is set to yes, the ship will supply the target ship and all of the ships that are following the target ship.\n\n\033OTemplate Outfit\033X\n\nWith this command, your ship will outfit the target ship with all wares in the selected template \(see: \033YTemplate Manager\033X\). Once the command is completed, the target ship will install all wares, and configuration will match the template requested. If supply entire formation is set to yes, the ship will outfit the target ship and all of the ships that are following the target ship with the requested template.</t>
 <t id="73">Template Manager</t>
 <t id="74">Templates offer the ability to save the entire design of a ship. Once saved, a template can be used to outfit a ship via various commands.\n\n\033OSave Ship Loadouts\033X\n\nA template is a blueprint for the entire configuration of your ship including weapons, missile, turret commands, autojump configuration, emergency jump, ware resupply, and more.\n\nWhen you launch the template manager from the player console, you will be able to save a ship to the template manager. Select add template, select a ship from the menu, and name the template.\n\nTemplates are used extensively throughout Litcube`s Universe systems to automate refitting. \033YMilitary Logistics &amp; Command Software \033Xhangar feature, \033YDockware Manager \033Xoutfitting, and the \033YSupply Command Software Ship\033X Template Outfit all make use of templates.</t>
 <t id="75">Trade Product Search</t>
 <t id="76">Search the entire known universe to find the best deals when selling wares or purchasing.\n\n\033OCan`t Find Stuff?\033X\n\nThis command, run on the player ship, lets you find stuff for sale so that you don`t have to ask me where to find it. It`ll look for wares, ships, or stations for sale in the entire Universe.\n\nIn order for the product to be searchable, you need to know of the station`s existence, and have PPP \(Player Property Present, for example, a satellite\).\n\nMode has two settings. Price will allow you to search for the best buy or sell price. Availability will search for the highest amount available at a station when searching for a buy, and the least amount when searching for a sale.\n\nWares required for the command to show up in the Trade menu can be found in the encyclopedia under Software and equipment commands.</t>
 <t id="77">Trade Reports</t>
 <t id="78">All property now keeps a detailed log of every transaction ever made. See a compiled list or individual reports.\n\n\033OSee A Record Of What Your Stuff Traded\033X\n\nTahlmorra requested trade reports, and got trade reports. Ad nauseam. There`s now trade reports for everything. All your ships and stations now carry a trade report that can be accessed from context menu Advanced sub menu. The reports are generated when anything you own buys or sells something. Trade reports are capable of numbers reaching quadrillions. There`s three types of trade reports.\n\n\033OTrade Report Type: Personal\n\033X\nAccessed by the Advanced context sub-menu, this trade report follows you wherever you go, whatever ship you are in. If you entered into a UT to pilot it, for example, the UTs ship report would be your own personal one. And when you exited the UT to go into another ship, the trade report follows you, but the UT`s trade report would be the same as it was before you jumped in. Included in personal reports is ships bought at a shipyard; though the equipping done through the shipyard is attributed to the individual ship.\n\n\033OTrade Report Type: Station/Ship\033X\n\nAccessed by the Advanced context sub-menu, ships and stations will generate their own trade reports. Station reports are generated by any ship that has the homebase set to it or an NPC trades with the station.\n\n\033OTrade Report Type: Archive\033X\n\nIn the Player Console, select the trade report archive. This will contain every single transaction all of your ships and stations ever made.</t>
 <t id="79">Tug</t>
 <t id="80">The tug is used to automate the hauling of ships back to a station via flagging a ship with a hotkey.\n\n\033OFunctionality\033X\n\nThe tug command is run on huge ships with a dock bay. When run, the tug will stay docked at its homebase waiting for you to flag a ship for it. When the tug sees that you have flagged a ship for tug, it`ll jump there, pick up the ship \(and others you may have flagged in the sector\), drop it off at the tug`s homebase, and dock again. This command makes capturing and recycling ships easy. It`s just another quick way to keep your shit together.\n\nFlagging a ship for tug is done via hotkey.\n\nThe Tug command`s menu allows you to configure strip functionality. Stripping is a command run on a ship that removes all of its wares and onto the ship/station where it`s docked. Often, a tug is used to collect derelict ships which are stripped anyway.\n\n\033OStrip functionality\033X\n\nThe Tug command menu allows for a few different strip options. In LU, stripping generally means removing all the wares from a ship and dumping them where it`s docked.\n\nNone: No stripping performed\nAt homebase: Ships are stripped upon the tug landing at its homebase, wares deposited onto homebase\nOn this ship: Ships are stripped upon docking with the tug, wares deposited onto tug\n\nThere`s two ways to flag a ship for tug.\n\nUse the hotkey when the ship to be tugged is targeted \(under interface\)\nOn the ship that needs to be tugged: run Flag ship for tug from the ship.\n\n\nObviously, the ship to be tugged needs to be owned by you.</t>
 <t id="81">Universal Bailing</t>
 <t id="82">Ship bailing can happen anywhere in the galaxy, from any race. A completely new system replaces the old.\n\n\033OIntroduction\033X\n\nA bail, is a ship that was abandoned by the pilot for reasons relating to self preservation. Universal bailing is described as bailed ships throughout the universe without the players involvement. In vanilla, bailing only happens through direct interaction by the player.\n\nLU has a universal bailing mechanic that completely replaces its vanilla equivalent.\n\nBailing has been changes in fundamental ways:\n\nOverall bail chance has been decreased.\nAll ships not owned by the player can now bail.\nAll ships can now cause a bail to occur.\nEach ship class has its own threshold hull strength below which they have a chance to bail \(larger ships have a lower threshold than smaller ones\).\nBail chance is dependent on four factors\nShip Class\nPilot Morale\nHull Strength\nRelative combat strength between the attacking and bailing ship\n\n\n\033OSalvagers\033X\n\nNPC Salvagers have been added the the universe. Salvagers fly around collecting bailed ships and dropped cargo containers. These included the freebies spawned at the start of a new game \(although they don`t cheat and must see the freebie before collecting it\).\n\nThings to keep in mind regarding NPC Salvagers:\n\nThey WILL take your hard earned loot if you delay in picking it up!\nYou CAN blow the hell out of them before they do \(if you don`t mind the rep penalty\)!</t>
 <t id="83">Universal Trader\n</t>
 <t id="84">A few changes have been made to the way UTs work in Litcube`s Universe.\n\n\033OIntroduction\033X\n\nUniverse Traders, or UTs, are ships outfitted with specific equipment that have the ability to trade on the player`s behalf. They search out trade opportunities and buy low, sell high. So start out with, all UTs are Sector Trader, or STs. Only until they reach a high enough level are they allowed to become UTs.\n\nUniverse Traders operate similarly to vanilla traders, with a few key changes regarding trader security and jump ranges.\n\n\033OPlayer Console Commands\033X\n\nTwo commands are available for UT`s in the Player Console.\n\nUT Ignore Stray Ware Warning: If you want to keep certain wares in the UT and not sell them, add those wares to this list to prevent unnecessary UT messages.\nUT Blacklist Wares: What it sounds like. If there are certain wares that you don`t want the UT to trade, add them to this list.\nSector Security Complaints: See the sectors your UTs think are too dangerous. Clean them up or send an MLCC intercept mission\n\n\033OSecurity\033X\n\nUniverse traders are more concerned with self-preservation than they previously were. To that effect, every UT regardless of level will equip itself with 6 Fighter Drones.\n\nAdditionally, UT`s will only trade in sectors where player-owned property is present \(PPP\). They will not jump into a sector where an enemy ship carrying more than 4 guns is within any player scan range.\n\n\033ORefueling\n\033X\nUTs will refuel if a target station is out of fuel range or the UT has less than 8 sector jumps worth of fuel.\n\n\033OUniverse Trader Levels &amp; Ranges\033X\n\nYou can turn your Sector Trader into a Universe Trader at level 8, like Vanilla. The UT will be less effective until it reaches level 11. The &quot;Buy&quot; distance of a trader is essentially its tether distance. The greater sell distance is to ensure that the UT doesn`t end up carrying cargo that it can`t sell. Additionally, the UT will use its jumpdrive until it detects that it has 8 jumps or less left in its fuel tank, at which time it will withhold buying or selling new wares and jump to refuel.</t>
 <t id="1001">SWLU Things To Know 1</t>
 <t id="1002">SWLU - XenonArchitect7\n\nStar Wars LU Mod-Specifics\n\n- SWLU is NOT a &quot;port&quot; or &quot;remake&quot; of Mikhail Skatchkav`s Star Wars Reborn mod. This is an original\n\tmod built from scratch, designed for LU specifically. Only ship assets were taken \(with permission\)\n\tfrom Skatchkav and most have been overhauled, reworked, and fixed from his original implementation.\n\n- SWLU recommended gamestarts for beginners:\n\t- Imperial Convoy\n\t- New Republic Merchant\n\t- New Republic Prospector\n\n- Each star wars faction has been assigned to a single X3AP faction. For example, all\n\tSeparatist ships belong to the Paranid. See the faction list.\n\n- Each star wars faction has its own sector where you may purchase its ships in one place.\n\tThere are still star wars ships scattered accross the X3 Universe, however, at\n\tthe normal race shipyards. When you start a game, your faction`s Star Wars sector\n\tis revealed on the map to start.\n\n- All LU and vanillia ships remain in the game. Star wars ships have simply been\n\tadded to each race rather than used to replace their existing ships. As of\n\t1.2.0, the NPCs no longer use the X3AP ships although the player can still\n\tbuy them.\n\n- Repair ship variants are hidden and rare, not purchasable. These ships are capable of\n\tmounting four repair lasers, which is 4x faster than your space suit. In the\n\tgalaxy, there is a hidden TIE Interceptor Repair Ship and a hidden X-Wing Repair\n\tShip. Good luck finding these!</t>
 <t id="1003">SWLU Things To Know 2\n</t>
 <t id="1004">- Repair lasers are scattered across the universe in ware containers. There are about ~20 in total.\n\tThey will always be found in groups of 2, and can be used for the repair ships. They cannot be\n\tbought or sold, and can only be used by the two repair ships \(or more if you reverse engineer\).\n\n- The YT-1300 model with the port-mounted cockpit \(millennium falcon\) is only obtainable through used\n\tship trade missions from the Rebels or Empire.\n\n- Some ships, like the YT-2400 Light Freighter, have rebel and imperial variants. Different\n\tengine color and different laser/missile compatibility.\n\n- Some ships, like the Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter, have color variants. Each ship type may\n\tshare the same name, but their descriptions will always specify variants. Turn\n\ton subtitles in-game to see descriptions on the ship info menu. Note that all ships can\n\tstill be repainted at the PHQ if you have &quot;color variations&quot; enabled in the graphics\n\tsettings. Some ships work better than others with this.\n\n- Star Wars ships may not be 100% covered by LU`s built-in bounce feature. Oddly-shaped ships will\n\tbe more prone to crash when docking/undocking, etc.\n\n- Certain capital ships, such as the Separatist Providence Dreadnought, have a strange quirk\n\twith docking availability. The Providence can dock 48 ships in star wars LU. The ship\n\tinfo screen in-game says fighter 0/48 and external 0/1. The ship can dock 48 ships TOTAL,\n\tmeaning you can`t have 48 fighters in the hangar and 1 freighter externally. So if you\n\thave 1 freighter docked externally, you can only have 47/48 fighters in the hangar, and\n\tthe 48th fighter will refuse to dock. Similarly, if you have 48/48 fighters docked, you\n\twill be stuck with 0/1 freighters docked, and will not be able to dock one with the\n\tProvidence. When you use ships like this as carriers with LU`s MLCC system \(you should\),\n\tI reccommend ignoring the external TS/M6 docking capability and only use the internal\n\tfighter docking. I don`t think MLCC can handle two different ship types for carrier\n\tfunctionality, but feel free to use the dual docking capabilities for personal ships\n\tor ships not in the MLCC system.</t>
 <t id="1005">SWLU Things To Know 3\n</t>
 <t id="1006">- All bombers can carry XL cargo containers. This includes M3 bombers such as the TIE Bomber.\n\n- All Star Wars ships contain AT LEAST four guns \(not counting transports and non-combat ships\).\n\tFor example, the TIE Fighter has 4 lasers, with two shooting out the left and two shooting\n\tout the right even though the ship model only has two visible areas where lasers emit.\n\n- Star wars ships, unlike X3`s commonwelath ships, mostly stick to their faction`s own lasers\n\tand cannot equip those of other factions. Ion cannons are an exception.\n\n- Star Wars TS, TP, TM ships have LU thruster trails, and the rest of the star wars ships do not. For\n\texample, the X-Wing`s engines glow but do not produce the long exhaust trails like\n\tthe rest of the X3AP ships. This was an arbitrary decision and can easily and quickly\n\tbe changed in the TShips file. I did this because TIE fighters would look strange with\n\texhaust, and ships don`t leave exhaust trails in Star Wars cannon.\n\n- Gamestarts of every faction are availible, each with a unique starting scenario.\n\tThere are no unlockable gamestarts.</t>
 <t id="1007">X3 Gameplay Changes</t>
 <t id="1008">- All lasers have double range from standard LU.\n- All &quot;Heavy&quot; lasers \(PAA, TBC, PALC, FBC\) have double rate of fire and half damage\n\tfrom standard LU.\n\n- SCHs can now be purchased in Circle of Labor in addition to Saturn 3.\n- PHQ now purchasable in Uranus in addition to Cloudbase Southeast.\n- OTAS MLCC docks now purchasable in Galactic Empire, Imperial Remnant in addition to \n\ttheir normal location Legend`s Home.\n- Galactic Empire, Imperial Remnant sectors also sell Teladi Trading Stations.\n- All vanilla corporation HQs now purchasable at vanilla shipyards nearest to their\n\tnormal location. For example, you can buy the Terracorp HQ dock in Argon Prime.\n- Advanced LU software upgrades such as Plutarch Tractor System are now availible at the\n\tSaturn Research Station in Saturn.\n- The goal of these added vendors is to make total war with the Argon or Terran factions \n\tpossible, without having to play nice to get vital stations.\n\n- SWLU adds many unknown sectors and Xenon sectors to the game, allowing more areas for combat and more\n\tpotential salvage hotspots for early-game.\n\n- 25% of all pirate ships will be models from any of the playable races. The other 90% are regular\n\tpirate ships. Pirates steal ships. This makes it more interesting.\n\n- Added civilians, traders to the Yaki and beefed up their millitary.\n\n- Made Interworlds more feisty at the start.\n\n- Yaki &quot;defend station&quot; combat missions no longer spawn Paranid enemies. Now it is Pirate/Xenon.\n- &quot;Defend station&quot; missions also no longer have the 2% chance to spawn Yaki enemies.\n\n- Unlike LU, factions are at war! Boron/Argon are at war with Terran/ATF \(Galactic Civil War\) and\n\tthere is also a war between the Teladi and Paranid \(The Clone Wars\). No war sectors. This\n\tjust means that the factions will shoot at each other when given the chance. Note that\n\tthis does not happen with the LU default gamestarts that remain in SWLU.</t>
 <t id="1009">SWLU Laser Notes</t>
 <t id="1010">- All &quot;Ion&quot; weapons have been rebalanced such that 80% of their total damage is shield damage and the other 20% is hull damage. They are used by all factions.\n\n- Factions that are missing laser slots simply use similar \(or ion\) lasers from other factions instead. For example, the separatists use PPCs for their capital laser.\n\n- The flak guns {SSC} {CFA} {FAA} are not really used by Star Wars LU, but remain in the game. Their sound effects also remain unchanged from vanilla.\n\n- While the correct faction`s lasers will be sold in the corresponding star wars sector, they continue to be built by their vanilla races in the galactic economy. This also goes for buying stations to make lasers yourself. For example, the {FBC} is an ion cannon used by all factions, but only the Terrans make it in vanilla LU, so you will need to buy factories from them if you want to make the gun yourself or if the star wars sectors become out of stock or unavailable.\n\n- The OCV Kyon Emitters paralyze each ship they hit, reducing their speed by 90% for 3 seconds upon impact.</t>
 <t id="2001">\033MROLL CREDITS\033X</t>
 <t id="2002">\033MROLL CREDITS FOR THESE AWESOME FOLK\033X\n\nSWLU Mod Team:\nXenonArchitect7 - Lead Mod Dev\nTormox - Animated shield texture, help with various large ship models\nLeytra - Help with some light maps, textures\nRocket Man - Discord moderator, testing, Prophet of Droidism, Encyclopedia Filler Outer\nArgonaut0201 - Author of &quot;SWLU Galaxy in Chaos&quot; official expansion\nPurls - Maintainer of SWLU est 2023\nTemetVince - Author of &quot;Alaankwa&quot; and implementation into SWLU\nBorgz Pony - SWLU Map image maker\nubiquitous_semaphore#9114 \\(Sem\\) - Helping Purls find and work on ships\n\nShip/Asset Models Credit:\n\(see SWLU ship list for detailed breakdown\)\nWarb Null\nDinoff\nJeroenimo\nMaxloef1990\nMikhail Skatchkov\nPSCO1\nSwefan Italia\nKlaus11\n\nSpecial Thanks:\nLitcube - Creator of LU, made all this possible\nJoubarbe - Author of Mayhem mod, invaluable help\nHector0x - Mayhem2 port testing and feedback\nScarps - Early help with audio and TIE cockpit textures\nTheXPGamers - Public testing and spreading the word</t>
 <t id="3001">\033RDon`t Click This\033X</t>
 <t id="3002">She packed my bags last night pre-flight\nZero hour nine AM\nAnd I`m gonna be high as a kite by then\nI miss the earth so much I miss my life\nIt`s lonely out in space\nOn such a timeless flight\n\nAnd I think it`s gonna be a long long time\n`Till touch down brings me round again to find\nI`m not the man they think I am at home\nOh no, no, no\nI`m a rocket man\nRocket man burning out his fuse up here alone\n\nMars ain`t the kind of place to raise your kids\nIn fact it`s cold as hell\nAnd there`s no one there to raise them if you did\n\nAnd all this science I don`t understand\nIt`s just my job five days a week\nA rocket man\nA rocket man\n\nAnd I think it`s gonna be a long long time\n`Till touch down brings me round again to find\nI`m not the man they think I am at home\nOh no, no, no\nI`m a rocket man\nRocket man burning out his fuse up here alone\n\nAnd I think it`s gonna be a long long time\n`Till touch down brings me round again to find\nI`m not the man they think I am at home\nOh no, no, no\nI`m a rocket man\nRocket man burning out his fuse up here alone\n\nAnd I think it`s gonna be a long long time</t>
</page>
</language>
